Please contact us for any inquiries
turkision@gmail.com
Episode 86
We slept in the enemy's bosom.
Just beside them.
We took place in their hearts.
We learned
their minds, souls, trades, faiths.1
We captured them.
It's time to awaken the ones
who sleep under the false light.
Now is time to wake up.
They took roots to these lands.
We'll break their branches and
root them up.
Every mob that finds swords...
can turn into an army.
But preparing a commander takes
decades.
Whatever they have among them...
intellectuals, scholars...
elders, commanders...
we'll destroy them all.
Wake up!
You are the ones who awakened
the first.
The ones who woke up to destroy.
You are more dangerous than this
poison in my hand.
According to Mari, a girl
with no one.
According to Turks, a helpless girl
serving Mari.
But our most capable killer.
I'll destroy their union...
from inside, right from the center.
Their commander showed
their weakness.
Let their weakness bring their
end, Cornellia.
If their best commanders Turgut
and Gündüz are getting on bad terms.
This will turn bloody.
Whose end will be caused
by this poison, sir?
Mari, who you've been living
with for years.
I buried my father.
My heart is burning, Osman.
He died before seeing
his grandson.
Umur Bey is a martyr.
We are witnesses to that.
You should be my witness that...
I'll take the lives of who
did this to him.
I don't doubt that at all, Osman.
My father's blood won't be forgotten.
I know it.
You are a strong woman.
You will overcome this too.
And I'll always be with you.
But if you allow me now...
I need to talk to Sultan Mesud now.
Yes, Osman.
You buried your dead.
Now, it's time to give answers, Osman!
My sultan.
There isn't a single move that I can't
answer for, my sultan.
What do you want me to answer?
You killed the vizier of the Seljuks
in front of my eyes!
You couldn't do it to me so
you did to him!
I won't waste breath to say
what you did.
The only words that will come
out of my mouth will be...
your death sentence.
My sultan.
Your decision is unjust.
If Vizier Alemşah was alive now...
he would tell everything.
But...
but his time was over.
If the heads don't speak...
then others will.
My sultan.
I'm your subject, a Seljuk commander,
Konur.
They will speak now, my sultan.
I considered my service to Vizier Alemşah
as serving you, my sultan.
I beg your forgiveness.
Stop gabbling and
speak the truth.
My sultan.
Vizier Alemşah have done many
tyranny with your name.
Even the ones I personally
witnessed...
are making it sure that
he deserves to be killed.
Who is holding the strings of the vizier?
My sultan.
Vizier Alemşah...
attempted to kill Osman Bey.
Isn't this what a rebel...
who tries to kill me deserves?
Tell me, Barkın.
Where and how did this happen?
Everything.
I wish I didn't go ahead.
I wish I didn't leave my uncle alone.
I wish we had died together.
Not you, Selvi.
I should've been under the ground.
I'm too ashamed to hold
my head straight.
End my shame, Malhun Hatun.
I couldn't protect, Umur Bey.
I'm afraid of my Allah.
I can't take my life.
Save me from this burden.
Enough!
I need the ones who killed my father,
Barkın.
Stop crying now and tell me
what happened!
Mongols.
Mongols did it
Who was the commander?
How many were they?
They were many.
I couldn't see it.
Neither Umur Bey nor I had any alps
survive.
In front of my eyes, they slaughtered
all my valiants.
When I was fighting with two Mongols...
I fell wounded.
When I was closing my eyes...
I saw Umur Bey fell too.
Give him some time, Malhun.
Don't you see how Barkın is?
He loved my uncle too.
They killed him in front of
his eyes.
He is worse than us now.
I buried my father.
The ones who killed him won't
even have graves.
I didn't come here to listen to tales,
Osman.
I know what I've seen.
You stabbed me on my back!
It's not a tale, my sultan.
Mingiyan will tell everything.
Speak.
How did you attack me?
Tell him how your grand plan was.
Tell the co-operation of
Geyhatu and the vizier.
Tell how that dagger ended up
on the sultan's back.
Speak.
Alemşah informed us when Osman
got captured.
We gave his dagger to your
helper.
Your helper Selman is loyal...
to great Geyhatu.
We were going to get rid of
Osman and you.
But Osman...
This won't clean your name, Osman.
They speak as you want to not
end up like the vizier.
My verdict is clear.
Let's say it's true.
What about the other truth?
Why did you agree with Emperor Andrenikos?
My sultan.
If you ask me about
my deal with the emperor...
the lord should answer that.
Boran.
Sultan, his grace.
Osman Bey.
I'm Aya Nikola.
I came here today to speak
the truth only.
I took Osman to the emperor
personally.
After all, he wanted us on his side
against Geyhatu and the Mongols.
It's just that.
You speak, Michael Kosses.
Sultan Mesud, your grace.
I've known Osman Bey for years.
We have fought together on the
battlefield many times.
I'm convinced that Osman Bey's
only goal...
is to protect these lands and
sustain peace and stability.
Everyone here knows the Vizier and
Geyhatu's intentions clearly.
Their goal is to destroy you, us,
everyone.
For this reason, they came with
flying fire.
Everyone, out.
What you say, what you show,
your witnesses...
I'm finally convinced, Osman Bey.
The dead deserved death.
But I can't let you kill Geyhatu.
Geyhatu is my captive, my sultan.
His death or survival...
is my decision.
If Geyhatu won't die...
then I get my right.
If you kill Geyhatu, Argun will
raze our lands.
He'll kill us all, Osman!
Is there anything better
than saving our lands?
My sultan.
Ever since my grandfather Süleyman Shah,
my father Ertuğrul Ghazi, we fight.
We were destroyed tens of times.
We died thousands of times.
We aren't afraid at all.
But...
if Geyhatu will live...
in return, I want the villages in
Yenişehir borders.
I want weapons for my alps to equip.
I want horses for a campaign.
And to hit those tyrants...
I want bows.
This jihad is our breath.
A nation not fighting to advance...
will lose its liberty first.
The existence of the Turks can only be
possible with conquest.
You always ride your horse forward.
You'll receive what you want, Osman Bey.
Cornelia!
I've been looking for you
all day. Where are you?
You wanted a pie last night.
So I went to get one.
My lady, are you alright?
Mari!
What's wrong?
Are you alright?
My nausea doesn't leave me.
It will leave in time.
Go to your tent and
get some rest.
Cornelia.
Come with me. Let's prepare
some meals.
Alright.
Mari.
Turgut Bey!
Tell me, Barkın.
Turgut Bey.
I admire you.
If someone has given my wife
to the enemy...
I would kill him.
Barkın.
If it was up to me, I would've
kiled him long ago.
He should be thankful for Osman Bey.
You are right.
You are right but...
one who does it once...
can do it again, Turgut Bey.
How can Osman Bey trust Gündüz?
I couldn't believe what I heard.
I tyrannized the women here.
It's true.
I understand everything.
Taking Orhan away from
his mother?
The one who does this to
a little child...
can do anything.
But Osman Bey made his decision.
It's not up to us to speak.
Sultan Mesud saved your life.
But not only your feet, even your horse
won't touch these lands again.
Get up.
I'm not Alemşah.
You can't kill me.
I'll come with an army.
I will destroy your tribe.
I'll rip your and your children's hearts!
Don't!
I'll make this tent your grave.
You killed my alps.
You...
burned my heart!
You made brothers kill
each other!
I will do much worse!
When Argun hears what you
did to me...
he'll move to slay you.
You should be afraid of what
Argun Khan will hear, not me.
Speak clearly, Osman.
Your treachery isn't only against
Islam...
not only Turks...
you betrayed much more people.
You won't die that easily.
You will die as you lived.
What did you do, Osman?
You will see that soon.
Osman!
Your dogs killed my father.
I'll leave your corpse
on here, Geyhatu.
Die, rat!
Malhun!
Long live Osman Bey!
You can't release him from here
with my father's blood on his hands.
It's not Osman's order.
It's the ruler's order.
Stay back, woman.
It's not just.
You can't release this tyrant!
Malhun!
Osman!
Malhun.
I've never seen any action fueled
by anger end well.
He is leaving with my father's blood.
Traitor!
May his destination be grave.
It will be, mother.
It will be.
He leaves the revenge
of his tribe.
What kind of loyalty is this?
I'll take it all.
Long live Osman Bey!
Don't make another mistake, Osman Bey.
I got what I want, my sultan.
I took his teeth.
He can't come to these lands again.
Untie commander Geyhatu.
Mingiyan!
Your tongue will be knot...
no knife be able to
unknot it.
If you speak, you are dead, Mingiyan.
If someone is dying...
it's me who is swinging
the sword.
Now get out of my face.
Osman is growing stronger.
But our enemy is taken away
as a captive.
An enemy more dangerous than ever
is borning, Kosses.
More than ever.
Kayı people!
The slanders on Osman Bey is
cleared away.
He is innocent of all his accusations.
I, Seljuk ruler, Sultan Mesud...
gave Osman Bey the lands he wanted.
The villages on Yenişehir borders
belong to Osman Bey now.
Long live Osman Bey!
Now, your lands expanded with
your new lands.
The borders are under your protection.
Soon, I'll send you troops.
The lands you give will be
our frontiers for new conquests.
The troops you send will
fight for Islam.
We all will struggle for
the world's order.
Be at ease.
We will be victorious.
Godspeed.
Boran.
My bey.
Inform the alps and the beys.
Call them to my tent this evening.
It's time for conquest now.
As you order, my bey.
The alps need a valiant such
as you.
Why would a stranger like
Turgut be the Head alp?
Turgut is an independent man.
What did he control so far
that he can control the alps?
You couldn't protect Umur Bey, Barkın Bey.
What are you talking about here?
Go and mind your own business.
Söğüt
Osman Bey is coming tomorrow.
I don't want problems.
Prepare everything.
Don't worry, Akça Dervish.
We won't shame you.
Thank you.
Salam Alaikum.
Alaikum Salam.
You look like a traveler.
We are all travelers on the road of
The Middle Way.
We want to reach Allah.
This is the first time I see you.
Where are you coming from?
Where are you going to?
We are coming from Semerkant
with my student.
We travel for our faith
and stay at public houses.
They call me İbrahim Fakih.
You are most welcome here.
Thank you.
Let's get you to your room.
-You should get some rest.
-On the contrary.
I've been sleeping for a long time.
I'm energetic and ready for the mission.
When our mission is Allah's path...
You are in the right place,
İbrahim Efendi.
I know. I know, brother.
I've been hearing Söğüt's
unbreakable unity.
You came before me, huh?
I'm at your service.
I poisoned Gündüz and Turgut.
The daggers will shine soon.
That poison will start a fire, Barkın.
It'll start with a tent...
then it will spread...
spread, spread...
that fire will burn Söğüt.
We've awaken.
They'll sleep forever.
Umur's death has shaken them.
We are sowing doubt on their minds.
The fear inside them will
turn into anger.
This fear is the fear of darkness, Barkın.
They can't see their enemies.
Kayı Tribe will surrender.
Who'll set the fire?
Mari's loyal servant Cornelia.
She'll start the war by killing
a beloved one.
What will I do?
With the name of Allah.
How can she not eat all day?
Mari needs to be careful with
this.
You are right, Ayşe Hatun.
She is pregnant now.
She should think for her child.
Yes.
I won't feel good. I should
prepare a salver for her.
Alright.
She'll be a great mother.
She will. Wouldn't she?
She is pretty, her baby is pretty.
With the name of Allah.
Put it here.
Enjoy it.
-Make sure that she eats it all.
-Alright.
We'll fight without disguises,
without hiding.
Inshallah, brother.
From now, we should be open and not
repeat the old issues.
Otherwise, there are people who hide
better than you and work with the tyrants.
Is there anyone more tyrant than one
who steps over the fallen?
Don't get arrogant with your position
and choose wrong words, Turgut Bey.
-Gündüz Bey, don't--
-Turgut Bey.
Now, we are saved from two troubles.
Just like arrows flying out of my bow.
Now, we'll march to the enemy.
Our target is İnegöl.
My bey.
When I see Nikola, anger flows
in my veins.
We'll avenge our brothers.
But our cause isn't a cause of revenge.
Our cause is Allah's words.
Thank Allah.
We know the interior of İnegöl very well.
We know the weak points of it's walls.
Master Akça.
Say it.
We hid the Greek Fire with Master Davut.
My bey.
There are two ways to take down
the walls.
We'll fill the round shots with fire.
They will stuck on the wall and explode.
Or...
capable alps will shoot them...
with fire arrows.
Master Davud.
My bey.
Where will we shoot, Master Davud?
The stones on the west are strong,
hard to destruct.
But the stones on the east are
weaker.
If we open a hole between
two sides.
We'll see the street leading
to Nikola's interior castle.
When we reach Nikola and behead him,
the castle is ours.
Do we have enough catapults?
We don't, my bey.
But if we wait for Sultan's help,
our catapults will be enough.
We'll start the siege early.
Sultan's help will join us if they come.
But say it. Nikola must be on
guard now.
Including the roads, everywhere
must be filled with traps.
Now...
How will we position these catapults...
this near to the castle?
It's delicious, Cornelia.
Do you want some?
I appreciate it, my lady.
You need to eat for your baby too.
I wish to see you as a mother too.
This feeling...
motherhood...
it's different.
I should go and help the women now.
Good night.
Good night, my lady.
We are awakened, my lady.
But you'll be sleeping forever.
Master Akça.
You are building the catapults.
You are the master.
Now say it, how long does it take
to build it when you have all components?
With all the components?
All of them.
Half a day.
My bey.
We should hide them in a caravan.
When we get closer to the castle,
you know it, these woods are thick.
They are close to the eastern side.
If we build the catapults there...
Nikola will see the flying fire in
the morning instead of the sun.
Master Davud.
My bey.
Is what Gündüz Bey says possible?
It's possible, my bey.
But...
a catapult that is made in the darkness
of the night...
Is no good for anyone.
It's half-moon. It'll be dark, Osman Bey.
If we use torches, we'll reveal
ourselves to Nikola.
It's not reasonable.
It'll be as Gündüz Bey says.
This is how we'll take İnegöl.
But we'll take İğnehisar first.
It'll be our quarters.
Then, we'll march to İnegöl.
Make your preperations.
Mari.
Turgut.
Are you alright?
I'm alright.
Who are you mad at?
Say it.
How did you know?
From here.
Ever since I've known you,
you are in some trouble.
One comes after the other.
I've never seen you sleep in peace.
True.
Our life is harsh.
But do you know how I stay patient?
With you.
I forget it when I see you.
Maybe I don't sleep in peace but...
when I close my eyes...
I see us.
Our growing child...
and beautiful days to come.
Our future...
will be beautiful.
It will be beautiful.
Söğüt
Welcome, Osman Bey.
Allah bless you.
Thank you.
Welcome, my bey!
No need.
How's business?
Thank Allah. Thank Allah, my bey.
-Thanks to you.
-Mashallah.
Mashallah.
Have a good day.
Good day, Hasan the Honey Seller!
Welcome, my bey.
-Thank you.
-You too, my bey.
Let us taste your honey.
It's the same with
the last one. Here.
With Allah's name.
Enjoy it, my bey.
Weigh this again.
Why should I weigh it again?
It's not fair that you ask the same
price for crushed apples.
Either put a different price
for the crushed ones...
and I'll pay separately...
or weigh the healthy ones only...
and I'll buy them.
Is this just for these two apples?
Look.
If I grant you this, there will be no
punishment for you in the afterlife.
Take it if you want.
I won't feel its loss.
But you adding haram to your profit
for two apples makes me feel bad.
The haram you eat is so bad that...
only the flames of hell can
cleanse it.
You are right.
I apologize.
Give me your blessing.
Take them as a gift.
I can't.
You will get what
you deserve.
If you take less, it's my suffering.
If you take more, it's your suffering.
Don't let either of us suffer.
May Allah give you a nice
working day...
and lot's of halal profit.
Thank you.
Efendi.
Mari! Mari!
Mari, are you alright?
Are you alright?
I'm not!
My stomach...
Here.
You look pale.
Did you catch a cold?
My inside is crushing!
I'm with you.
Turgut, our baby...
Baby is fine.
Speak well.
The baby is good.
Ayşe Hatun's meal...
What?
Mari! Mari!
Mari!
Mari! Turgut Bey!
What's happening here?
Cornelia, I don't know!
I don't know what's wrong.
-Turgut...
-Mari!
Are you alright, my lady?
Turgut, our baby...
It'll be alright.
We'll go to Kumral Abdal.
Doesn't Söğüt have laws?
Why are you intervening?
Who are you? Tell me.
This poor man is İbrahim Fakih.
This is my studend İshak.
It's my duty to correct the
mistakes I witness.
Are you on the wrong side that
you are disturbed?
Do you know who you are
talking to?
You can be a sultan or a bey.
I know what's right and
I speak it.
It doesn't matter.
We need men who speak the truth.
And this poor man is Osman Bey.
Here, this weapon is all I have.
But my weapon...
doesn't let wrongs live
in Söğüt.
Thank you, Osman Bey.
Thank you.
Tell me.
Where are you coming from?
We are coming from Semerkant.
You brought Semerkant's smell to Söğüt.
I'm glad you came, İbrahim Fakih.
Salam Alaikum.
Alaikum Salam.
Welcome, my bey.
Thank you.
We have hot soups.
Come in.
Let's get in.
İbrahim Fakih.
Please.
Less or more, haram is the same, you said.
You saved my shopekeeper
from great pain.
Thank you.
We believe that Allah gives livelihood
to all that is created.
A human's part is searching
for their livelihood in halal ways...
and not follow the devil's path...
and go haram ways to do so.
You spoke greatly.
The devil is the most ancient and cruelest
enemy of the humans.
Muslims should put effort
to not let the devil triumph.
You are right, Osman Bey.
The devil can sway the Muslims.
It can make brothers fight.
It takes such shapes that...
it hides so well that...
it take place between your
eyebrows but...
you still can't see it.
It flows in your veins
like poison...
but you can't know before you bleed.
Help Alps! Help!
Help!
- Help!
- Kumral Abdal, Mother Selcan, help!
Help!
My baby...
I won't leave you or the baby.
Kumral Abdal will heal you.
Mari?
Don't go.
Don't go, darling.
Mari, don't go.
Mari?
- Mari!
- Mari, my girl?
What happened?
Kumral Abdal, tell me something.
Tell me she didn't die,
tell me she's well.
Tell me.
There is nothing we can do, Turgut Bey.
No!
My beautiful!
Wake up my beautiful darling.
Don't go, please!
Please!
I couldn't protect her, mother.
I couldn't protect my hatun and my baby.
What kind of father am I?
What kind of bey am I?
Mother Selcan, I couldn't protect them.
I couldn't protect you.
Don't say that, son. Don't say that.
My beautiful.
I couldn't protect you.
They poisoned her.
They killed her!
They poisoned her!
How could you kill her?
How?
You did this!
Cornelia, stop!
What are you saying?
They poisoned her!
They did it!
Why would anyone do that?
They poisoned her! They did!
Know your place, hatun!
What are you saying?
They killed Mari.
You say you come from Semel camp.
Where are you going?
My wish is to go to Contantinniye
We're heading west.
We'd like to establish science in Sogut.
Stay here.
Why would you like me
to stay here, Osman Bey?
There is no establishment of a
government without knowledge.
Of course, we got alfakis and scholars.
But a government that has more
alps than alfakis can never be.
For that reason...
...stay here.
Even if it gets established,
it could not be able to stand.
Science and knowledge.
Without them, the cause of
world conquest is impossible.
When we see the ones that
have the same cause as us...
...we get happy.
May Söğüt be granted with your wisdom.
My Sheikh!
Salam aleikum!
Alaikum salam, Osman Bey!
My Sheikh, this is İbrahim Fakih. He came
to Söğüt from Semerkant.
İbrahim Fakih.
I don't remember
sending you an invitation.
But welcome anyway.
The light of Oghuz Sheikh Edebalı.
A guest without an invitation is better.
Osman Bey wants me to camp in Söğüt.
Thank Allah for granting
me with meeting you!
I would like to speak to
you longer, İbrahim Fakih.
With pleasure, Sheikh Edebalı.
Akça Dervish made
arrangements in the tavern.
Let's go over there and have a chat.
My Sheikh.
After you.
They poisoned her.
They poisoned my hatun and my baby.
At least, let's get them inside.
We shouldn't keep
them here for all to see.
I promise you, we'll
fınd out who did this.
Come on, let them go. Let them
go so that we can carry them.
Alps!
Let us carry them, come on.
Come on.
Turgut Bey!
Stop!
Don't do it!
Gündüz! Gündüz!
You killed her! You killed Mari!
You killed my baby!
Gündüz, you killed my hatun!
Why Gündüz? Why? Why!?
Why?
What are you saying Turgut?
Why would I do such a thing?
You did it before and did it again!
What do you want from us, Gündüz?
What did you want from me?
See what's going on?
They started falling apart
without us making a move.
I didn't do it.
I won't forgive you Gündüz.
Stop Turgut, stop!
How could I stop?
My life is over!
Turgut Bey! Turgut Bey!
Turgut Bey.
The truth will eventually come out.
Don't do anything you may regret later on.
Akça Dervish,...
...praise be! You did a
good job with this place.
You do your job well.
Thank you, Osman Bey!
I try my best.
The food was delicious.
Bless your hands!
I'm happy you enjoyed your meal.
So, you came all the way from Semerkant.
And you are İbrahim Fakih.
What brings you here?
I got many reasons to be
here, Sheikh Edebalı.
I will seek wisdom till the day I die.
Reading is my passion
I read about Ebu Hafs
Necmettin Al Nasafi as well.
Human improves via reading.
You came from Semerkant
and they call you İbrahim Fakih.
It would be better to listen
Alaaddin Semerkandi from you.
I know Alaaddin Semerkandi...
...from my first teacher, my ancestor.
Now, I transfer his information into
my students.
It would be a pleasure for me
to tell you that, Sheikh Edebalı.
If Allah permits, Kayı and Söğüt
will be granted with your wisdom.
"Whoever has knowledge may they share it."
It is a good deed to share
knowledge, Osman Bey.
It would be a pleasure.
- Bey Sungur.
- My bey?
Get the horse ready.
Yes, my bey!
I bid you farewell.
My Sheikh.
İNEGÖL CASTLE
What is going on again, Nikola?
There is a disturbance in your castle.
What do you think
Osman will do now, Koses?
You're the only one
worried about that, it seems.
You tell me.
He entered our castles.
Learned about everything.
Turks take what they explore, Koses.
But you entered all the
way to his tent, Nikola.
I don't want war.
I just want power.
That's it.
But Osman has gotten stronger
by defeating his enemies one by one.
Don't do this Nikola.
Vizier and Geyhatu were
our enemies as well.
Tell me what you really want.
Balance.
I want balance,...
...Koses.
But Osman...
...has upset the balance.
He could attack anytime.
If I remember correctly...
...the same Osman handed me Harmankaya.
The same castle you took from me
by the balance, you set up with Vizier.
That one.
That's why I have no doubt
about who to trust, Nikola.
Don't worry.
You're not aware...
...Koses.
I hope when you do realize,
it won't be too late for you.
Like you said...
...let's stay friends.
For now.
Because the war is at the door.
Would you allow me, mother?
Everything was great with
you, mother of my child.
Everything was great.
Why did our story end
like this, mother Selcan?
What did we do to deserve this?
We'll find out who did this, son.
We'll find who did this, eventually.
She's in your hands.
Look after Mari.
Tell me, Cornelia.
What did Mari eat before she died?
This.
This is it.
She ate this.
Ayşe Hatun gave me this.
Kumral Abdal, Mari ate
that before she died.
Tell us Kumral Abdal...
...tell us something.
Get us out of this dark wellhole
She got poisoned.
It's a very effective poison.
Hide the plate, Kumral Abdal.
Osman Bey would like to see it.
My beautiful Mari.
Was this how you were supposed to die?
Who would kill a pregnant hatun?
Who could be this brutal?
I had nobody besides her.
She was like my sister.
Ayşe Hatun.
Is this the plate you gave?
Ayşe?
I didn't do it, mother.
I didn't do it.
You say Mari.
Mari.
Pregnant Mari.
How could I kill Mari?
How could I kill an unborn baby?
I swear, I didn't do it.
If Allah permits.
The messenger on the road...
...why is it, Nikola?
To let the emperor know of my opinions.
Also,...
...Geyhatu is gone.
The deal is over.
That's true.
Instead of making a new deal...
...you want war.
It's not me who wants war.
Osman. Osman himself.
Osman.
Soldier.
Kayı Bey Osman Bey is coming.
Quickly, soldier! Quickly!
Osman Bey!
Welcome!
Happy to be here, Nikola!
Happy to be here!
What is the state of these roads, Nikola?
There are soldiers everywhere.
Caution.
I like caution.
Is it because of us?
If so, let us know.
We'll act accordingly.
Of course not, Osman Bey.
We're friends now.
If that was the case...
...could you get into
this castle like this?
Let's say you did.
Could you leave with no harm?
I could.
I did it before.
If I were to take it...
...you would hear the rumble.
How could Turgut Bey do that?
Why would Gündüz Bey
want to hurt Mari Hatun?
He doesn't know what he's doing, Cerkutay.
This is the hardest test one can have.
He suffers real bad.
May Allah never grant that
type of suffering on anybody.
Nobody can bear that type of suffering.
You're right.
He's really hurt.
But...
...Gündüz Bey,...
...Ayşe Hatun,...
...I don't know.
Would they ever do such a thing?
One side of me says no...
...but wasn't it a short time ago
when they handed Mari to Vizier?
I hope that's not the case.
Sister!
Stop!
I don't think we need war or rumble.
We're the men that
destroyed Vizier and Geyhatu.
Peace be with us.
Exactly!
As Koses says, Osman Bey...
...war shouldn't even be the discussion.
Right?
Argus, quickly!
Tell our cooks...
...to arrange a table for Koses
and Osman Bey, quickly!
No.
I won't stay to eat.
I'm heading to the tent.
I'm coming with you, Osman Bey.
He still looks me in the eye.
Has no shame.
Still.
We'll find it out.
But, I told you, Turgut Bey.
I'll tell you again.
You're full of rage.
If it's you Gündüz...
...if it's you...
...I will end you with Mari's dagger.
If it's you.
What kind of poison is that, Gündüz Bey?
I didn't do it, Bala Hatun.
I didn't do it!
Don't you see what kind
of slander I fall victim to?
I didn't do it.
Tell me Kumral Abdal.
Look into my eyes and tell me.
What happened to my Mari?
What happened to my baby?
Tell me, Kumral Abdal.
The food was poisonous.
The baby died first...
...then, Mari Hatun.
The poison that came out of the food...
...was found in Gündüz Bey's tent.
Stop!
Turgut Bey!
Turgut Bey! Turgut Bey don't!
Turgut Bey! Turgut Bey!
Stop!
Turgut Bey! Don't! Please!
Turgut Bey!
What is happening here?
Stop!
Turgut Bey!
What is this?
What is happening here?
Tell me!
Turgut!
This man you call brother...
...took my wife!
He took my life!
What are you saying?
He cut my breath!
I will cut your breath too, Gündüz Bey!
I will end you, Gündüz Bey!
You are done!
You are making no sense right now.
Turgut! Turgut!
Mari!
Is this true, brother?
Brother!
I didn't. I didn't
You are lying!
You are lying, Gündüz!
You are lying to me!
You took my Mari away from me!
Turgut!
Stop for a moment!
Take my brother to the prisoner tent
for now!
Come on!
No, Osman Bey!
Let me, let me go!
-My Mari! My Mari!
-Calm down! Calm down!
Turgut! Stop!
Brother...
...stop for a second!
Stop for a second!
Stop for a second.
Brother!
I am so sorry.
But...
...you died for a very important cause.
I will pray for you until my last breath.
Mari!
Get out.
I am sorry!
Forgive me!
I left you alone!
But look, I am here now!
Your brother is here.
Let's go home.
I promise you I will never let anyone
hurt you again!
Please, Mari!
Please don't leave me.
You are my only family!
Come on, we are going home.
Wake up.
Please!
I won't give you my sister.
I won't!
Hatuns, try to remember.
Didn't you see anyone strange in the tribe
or near Gündüz Bey's tent?
No.
Didn't you suspect anyone?
None?
We didn't see anyone, Bala Hatun.
Now leave.
Try hard to remember.
Come to me at once if you remember
anything.
Come on.
All right, Bala Hatun.
All the evidence lead to them.
What if they did it?
We couldn't protect her.
Aygül, stop saying that!
Neither Gündüz nor Ayşe would do such
evil, I know it!
I hope so.
What is this, mother?
Son...
...I will go talk to him again, all right?
Poison was on the plate...
...the bottle was in their tent.
Everything leads to my brother.
But...
...my brother...
...would never do such a thing to a
pregnant woman!
No way!
No way he would do it!
You are right, my Bey.
But don't forget his latest actions.
He separated Malhun from her baby.
He exiled us from the tribe.
He delivered Mari to the Vizier.
My father turned out to be a traitor.
No one surprises me anymore.
What do the hatuns say?
Did they see anything?
No, my Bey.
No one saw anything.
I am fine, Ayşe.
I am fine.
How could this happen to us, Gündüz?
We didn't hurt anyone.
Who did this to us?
Whoever benefits from killing Mari...
...and blaming us did it.
May my Allah save us from this slander,
my Ayşe.
Amen.
She is gone.
Mari is gone, with an innocent baby.
Tell me, Gündüz.
Can you be this evil?
I didn't do it, mother.
Would I ever hurt a pregnant woman?
You did before.
Didn't you send Mari yourself?
What should I do?
What should I do, what should I say now?
What kind of evil is killing an innocent
woman who carries a baby?
How can you think I would do such an evil,
mother?
Especially Ayşe.
I am so sorry about Marİ.
My heart is burning for her.
But Allah is my witness I am not involved
in this.
Know that if I find who did it...
...I will kill them myself.
We had just knitted booties for her baby.
She was so happy, mother.
Pregnancy looked beautiful on her.
What kind of an evil is this, mother?
Don't, my Ayşe.
Don't.
What do we do now?
This doesn't make sense, my Bey.
Would Gündüz Bey do this in the open if he
wanted to kill Mari?
He wouldn't. He wouldn't, Bala!
I agree with you.
Something doesn't sit right with me.
My only wish is that...
...you find them.
I won't let this incident stop
the conquest.
The preparations will continue.
While there is a traitor among us?
If it is Gündüz, he must have leaked
everything.
If it is someone else, they are already
outside.
This is what the enemy wants.
Maybe this is what it is all about.
I won't make them happy.
The conquest will continue no matter
what.
You will find those traitors.
My Süleyman Şah's trust is in worthy
hands.
Everyone can walk on a straight road, son.
But only those who are brave like
Osman Bey...
...can walk these bumpy roads.
Your word is an order for us, my Bey.
We will certainly find the traitor.
We will.
We will, mother.
Apple, red apple.
You are a Turk. This is more than an apple
for Turks.
The red apple symbolizes a dream.
A far-away dream.
A dream impossible to reach.
Good.
You are with me because your mind works
different from them.
You are after the reality, not the dream.
I want a state ruled by fear,
growing as its people fear it.
So, my way is your way.
A dark way.
And we are moving forward.
Mari is dead, Gündüz is imprisoned.
Kosses, Turgut... All of them are about to
turn against Osman.
Everything goes as we wish.
Not enough!
What keeps them together is a dream.
And we will crash that dream.
A Şed Ceremony will be held in the tavern.
We will destroy that place.
We will not only kill them but also...
...we'll be there...
...cry for them and eat their halvah.
Keeping us here and Gündüz there won't
work out, Osman Bey!
I will bury my sister with her baby
in her womb!
Just say whatever you will and do whatever
you will do!
I don't believe my brother did
such a thing.
What are you saying, Osman Bey?
Did you forget what he had done when you
entrusted him your tribe?
And then what he had done to my Mari.
It's all out there! How can you not think?
I say I don't think so.
I am not saying I am sure.
The justice will be given!
What is justice?
Tell me, Osman Bey, what is justice?
Didn't the poison come out of Gündüz's
tent?
What proof are we looking for?
When it comes to your brother,
the scales of your justice...
...which you do not stop speaking of,
do not be disturbed!
I am the nation of the prophet who
said that...
...he will not even favor his children
so that the right will be found.
Even if it is my brother ow my own
child...
...I show no mercy.
I do what is right.
Then do!
Speak frankly, Osman Bey.
Why do you think that Gündüz didn't do it?
Tell us if you know anything.
You all know about the problems between
me and my brother.
Everyone does.
All this time you've been holding back
your anger.
I know that too.
But those who want to hurt Kayı will try
to use the beys first.
How?
They killed my Mari to harm your tribe.
Are you telling me this?
I can't judge this issue.
Be patient.
Kosses...
...be patient.
Söğüt
Enjoy.
You've been hiding in Söğüt for years and
they never suspected any of you.
Because you are the children of darkness.
You made them believe in your loyalty.
It is time. Söğüt will burn.
Gunpowder is in apple sacks.
You will carry sacks of apples here.
As they think they are meeting
the Şed Ceremony...
...they will be torn into pieces.
Quick!
Hurry up!
Give it to me.
All right, go.
Nothing will stop the conquest.
You will deploy the archers
on the mountain.
Sure, my Bey.
If help comes and...
...we seem to be taking over
İnhisar...
...we will get around it first.
As you order, my Bey.
Horsemen are ready to strike
the incoming caravans.
My Bey...
...İnhisar is asleep.
There is no one but a few patrols on
the roads.
As you wished so.
Two alps are waiting in İnhisar according
to your order.
Then we will go to İnhisar immediately.
If you come across something that you can
solve by talking...
...don't ever touch your swords.
We will go as shadow and...
...destroy like a hurricane.
But...
...to build a home.
Right, Akça?
This is a conquest, my Bey.
We restore the place we conquer.
We do!
You will come with me, Akça.
We will go after them.
We will have your Şed Ceremony...
...before the conquest.
It suits such a virtuous master!
Come on.
You will leave some of the alps here for
guarding.
We will go to Mari's funeral first.
After there...
...we will go to the Şed Ceremony.
As you order, my Bey.
Harmankaya Castle
I swear to my Allah that...
...I will inflict the worst pain in the
world...
...on the traitors who took you
away from me...
...killed our unborn child,
and made you suffer...
...in front of my eyes.
But my pain stays.
It always will.
I trusted you with my sister.
You told me not to worry.
Is this your loyalty?
Is this your love?
You couldn't protect her!
They killed my sister and my nephew!
I won't let them get away with this!
We won't, Kosses.
We won't.
I will kill everyone who took her from me
with my own hands!
You won't do it alone.
Together.
I don't understand at all.
How can a man like Gündüz Bey kill
a woman?
I know the limits of Gündüz's anger well.
Does he do evil?
He does.
People...
But I also know that Gündüz wouldn't be
able to look me in the eyes like that...
...if he had hurt Mari.
I don't know them as much as you do.
But I've heard what he had done.
Besides, all the evidence lead to them.
Let's say they did it.
Why would they leave the bottle in
the tent?
A smart person wouldn't.
You are also right, Bala Hatun.
But...
...Gündüz Bey may have considered this.
We will solve this in a short time.
But we are late for the Şed Ceremony.
Come on, hatuns.
Wait, girl.
Don't you hear me? I am telling you I am
waiting for someone.
Who is this important person?
What are you hiding from me?
Can I come in?
Come in, girl!
They are here, Selcen Mother.
Who is it?
You are too curious, Aygül.
You will see when they come.
Stop bothering me.
Something is up with you since
the morning.
Do you know who it is?
Kayı.
Run to your mother.
Son!
My son!
Mother!
Oh, my son!
My dear!
My dear son!
I missed you so much, baby.
Where's apple are these?
They came from Amasya.
Amasya.
Then Sheik Nail Effendi must have
sent them.
It is the tradition.
Sheik's send each other whatever grows
in their lands.
Many people love Sheik Edebalı.
Many Sheiks sent gifts from all kinds of
lands.
My Sheik is the light of Oghuz!
Did you miss me too?
I missed you.
My Kayı!
My son!
No one will separate us ever again.
I will always keep you next to me,
my baby.
Is there anything more beautiful than
the reunion of a mother and her child?
Thankfully.
Who knows how you felt when
you had a child...
... after all this time, Bala Hatun?
I am sure what you've been through was
hard.
It was a trial, Selvi Hatun.
No one knows or can choose it.
Aygül!
You finally reunited with your Kayı!
Thankfully, mother.
How can I pay you, mother?
There is nothing to pay.
You paid his foster mother.
From now on, you will be the mother
of your child.
This is an important day.
-Peace be with you.
Thank you.
Peace be with you.
-Peace be with you.
Thank you.
In the name of Allah!
Make way!
May peace be with you, people of sharia.
May peace be with you.
Tell me...
...who is our journeyman you wish to be
licensed and what is his profession?
Working on the grass, under the sky.
Eager to fight on the battlefield.
Wishes your prayers.
Shepherd Akça, carpenter journeyman.
He is in your presence...
...with the hope of being a master.
In the name of Allah!
He is done.
We dressed you on the outside...
...may Allah fill you on the inside.
Amen.
Respect the truth and sharia in your
profession.
Control your hands and tongue.
Use your scale straight.
To turn Söğüt into a dark corridor...
...the light has divided the darkness
but I will reunite it.
There will not be a single point in this
land where darkness does not rule.
Light of Oghuz or Börü of the Sky...
...no one will be able to stand against
us.
Drown in the firelight and perish!
I, the Lord of the Darkness...
...will hide in the dark.
Until we destroy you all one by one...
...until there's no one left.
Please contact us for any inquiries
turkision@gmail.com